emeasupport.org 2013-09-02

# Privacy Policy | FamilySearch.org

The privacy of your personal information is important to The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and its affiliated legal entities (referred to in this policy collectively as “the Church,” “we,” “us,” and similar terms). This privacy policy is intended as a general statement regarding collection and use of personal information for Church-affiliated websites. We strive to collect, use, and disclose personal information consistent with the laws in the countries in which we collect personal information. This privacy policy applies to this website, which is owned and operated by the Corporation of the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, the Corporation of the Presiding Bishop of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, or FamilySearch International (as noted specifically on the first page of the website).

In selected jurisdictions, the Church-affiliated entities may adopt unique privacy policy provisions to reflect the requirements of applicable local laws. When a separate provision is deemed necessary, notice will be provided.

You can visit most Church websites without providing any personal information. When personal information is requested, the Church adheres to the following privacy principles regarding how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information.

## Privacy Practices

**Information Collection, Consent, and Use.** When you create an LDS account, register on a Church website, add profile information, or take other similar actions, we may collect or obtain from you or your membership records (if applicable) information including, but not limited to, your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, contact or profile preferences, and Church unit information. We will use such information to allow us to contact you, to fulfill your requests, to seek your voluntary feedback on website features or content, and to help fulfill the mission of the Church. We may also use your personal information for internal purposes, including auditing, data analysis, and research. We will use your information for no other purposes unless we specifically inform you otherwise and obtain your prior consent if legally required. We will also make you aware of options to opt out of using or opt in to use (as required by law) certain features. Moreover, we grant individuals the opportunity to object to certain uses of their information.

If you are a member of the Church, it is understood that membership information, including contact details, are shared on a limited and restricted basis between Church members for internal Church purposes, including over the Internet (with your prior consent if required by law). With respect to the privacy of your personal information, as a Church member you have given your implied or actual consent (as required by law) for the Church to use your personal information for Church purposes. If personal information is to be used for any other purpose, it will be used only with your prior consent.

**Content Submissions.** When you submit additional content through any Church website, such as, but not limited to, sending messages, engaging in online chats, replying to surveys, uploading photos, uploading video clips, making personal online notes, writing in an online journal, or using a similar feature, your information will be stored on our system. While we intend that certain submissions using features on Church websites are to remain private (for example, personal online notes, journaling, and so forth), we cannot guarantee the complete privacy of such submissions and may in some instances choose, or be legally required, to disclose such information to third parties as outlined in this policy. Some information you provide to the Church websites will be submitted with your express agreement that the submission is to be shared publicly. In such instances, others will have access to any personal information within such submissions. We recommend using caution when selecting which information you choose to include in such submissions to avoid causing harm or injury, or risk of harm or injury, to yourself or others.

We are under no obligation to monitor such content, but we reserve the right to do so at our sole discretion, and we are authorized to block or remove content we deem inappropriate or objectionable. We prohibit postings or submissions in any form to any Church website, using any available tool, whether intended to be private or shared with the public, that are obscene, lewd, lascivious, filthy, violent, harassing, defamatory, libelous, tortious, illegal, threatening, or otherwise inappropriate or objectionable. Since we do not review all content submitted through every feature on every Church website, we cannot guarantee that we will be able to take protective measures in the event you provide content disclosing information about a person that is a victim of harm or abuse or is at risk of becoming a victim of harm or abuse.

When we become aware of content posted on a website that we consider offensive or that could compromise the privacy of personal or confidential information (yours or another person’s), we will make a good-faith effort to block or remove such content.

**Retention.** We retain collected personal information for a reasonable period of time to fulfill the collection purpose and then delete it from our records, with the exception of limited historical data and membership information retained as part of a permanent genealogical or Church historical record.

**Access.** We endeavor to maintain the accuracy of personal information and rely on you to ensure your personal information is complete and accurate. You may verify, correct, or remove your personal information through your website-specific registration, through your profile, or through LDS account, where applicable. For information taken from your Church membership record, your personal information can only be updated by making changes to your Church membership record. Such changes must be made by contacting the clerk in your Church unit and requesting the change. If you experience problems with modifying or updating your personal information, you can contact us by sending an e-mail to [DataPrivacyOfficer@ldschurch.org](mailto:DataPrivacyOfficer@ldschurch.org).

## Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties

We regard your personal information as confidential and do not sell it to anyone. We do not share your personal information with other parties except in the following circumstances (or in other instances where we specifically inform you and obtain your prior consent):

**Third-Party Providers.** We may provide personal information to third parties for their use in performing internal functions on our behalf (payment processing, maintenance, security, data analysis, hosting, and so forth). In such instances, the providers will be contractually required to protect the personal information from additional use or transfer in accordance with this privacy policy and industry standards.

**Church Entities.** We may transfer personal information to any Church-affiliated entity to accomplish Church purposes. For membership information transfers from the European Union, we rely on standard clause agreements between Church entities in compliance with European Union requirements. For online submissions of personal information, we understand an individual’s submission to be an affirmative act, indicating informed consent to the processing of the data as well as informed consent to allow the transborder data transfer to the United States of America, where applicable, for the purposes for which it was provided.

**Legal Requirements.** We may access and disclose your personal information, posts, journal entries, online chats, personal notes, content, or other submissions to any Church website if we have a good-faith belief that doing so is required by a subpoena or other judicial or administrative order or otherwise required by law. Additionally, we may disclose your personal information and other information where we, in good faith, deem it appropriate or necessary to prevent a violation of our other agreements; to take precautions against liability; to protect the rights, property, or safety of the site, of any individual, or of the general public; to maintain and protect the security and integrity of our services or infrastructure; to protect ourselves and our services from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against third-party claims or allegations; or to assist government law enforcement agencies.

## Protecting Information

We use technical and organizational measures to protect the personal information we receive against loss, misuse, and unauthorized alteration, and to protect its confidentiality. We regularly review our security procedures in order to consider appropriate new technology and methods. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.

## Third-Party Data

Where local law permits, you may submit personal information, including contact information, about someone other than yourself (in other words, third parties) to allow the Church to make contact, make a delivery, or otherwise meet your request. The information collected will be used solely to facilitate your request. When providing personal information about anyone other than yourself, you must obtain the other person’s informed consent if legally required.

## Passive Data Collection: Tracking Technologies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a browser when a user visits a website or a small data file that may be saved on your computer’s hard drive that usually includes an anonymous unique identifier. A clear GIF is a graphic file, rather than a text file, that is similar in function to a cookie. We use these and similar tools in our effort to improve individual site experiences. We do not link the information we store in cookies, clear gifs, or other tracking technologies to any personally identifiable information. When an individual requests pages from a Church site, our servers may also log the user’s IP address in order to improve site administration. This information is used to produce usage statistics to help us better meet the needs of individual users and to determine specific interests. We do not link the IP address to any personal information.

## Policy Compliance and Questions Regarding the Privacy of Personal Information

We have a Church data privacy officer to help ensure compliance with this privacy policy and answer questions about data privacy or security issues. This officer helps educate employees concerning compliance. Inquiries concerning this privacy policy or the security of personal information processed by the Church may be sent through e-mail, fax, or mail to:

801-240-1187 (fax)  
Data Privacy Office  
50 E North Temple St. Rm. 1880  
Salt Lake City, UT 84150 

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect information from children under age 13 on most Church websites. Any Church website that collects children’s information will do so only with the prior express and informed consent of the child’s parent or guardian in compliance with applicable law. We strongly recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet, and we encourage parents to teach their children about safe Internet use practices.

## Third-Party Links

We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any third-party sites. For your own protection, you should review the policies of other sites to ensure they meet your personal expectations of privacy.

## Future Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of the privacy policy at any time. When we make changes to the privacy policy, we will post the changes on this page and update the revision date at the bottom of the privacy policy. We encourage users to check the privacy policy from time to time to remain informed of any changes.

## Effective Date 

This version of the privacy policy became effective on September 1, 2010.
